Esther Mureithi

Frontend Software Engineer

4+ years of software development experience. With proven skills in developing reusable and scalable frontend web app code that has flawless UI experience using tools like React JS and Material UI. Eager to continue tackling more complex problems and develop more human centered products.

esthermureithi27@gmail.com

+254 700190486

Nairobi, Kenya

github.com/wan-mureithi 🧲

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Nash Financial Services

05/2021 - 04/2023 Upperhill, Nairobi

Description

- Implemented business features using React Js and Redux toolkit for integration.
- Analyzed UI designs from Figma and requested for necessary APIs through Jira tasks on specific sprints.
- Maintained code in different workflows and environments using Git.
- Reviewed code on to be sent to the repository for features that I owned.
- Owned the frontend web development process. This included documentation, development and testing.
- Participated in Scrum sessions and business requirement gathering sessions and sprint planning.

Software Developer

Interswitch Kenya

06/2020 - 05/2021 Westlands, Nairobi

Description

- Created reusable UI components for key features like business registration and payment links using React JS.
- Deployed version two of the Quickteller Business web app into a dockerized environment.
- Organized my work on Trello to keep my team updated.
- Analyzed designs created on Adobe XD and developed the UI. Pushed the work to QA for testing.

Software Developer Intern

Octagon Data Systems

07/2018 - 12/2018 Hurlinghum, Nairobi

- Worked on a mobile app created an API using PHP and implement business logic using Java.
- Developed an inhouse web app to handle inventory of company tools for engineering team using PHP, HTML and CSS.
- Ran SQL queries on MSSQL client databases to diagnose issues that clients are having using the ERP.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Computer Science University of Nairobi

09/2019

SKILLS



PROJECTS

Zoho Payment Gateway (11/2022 - 01/2023)

- Successfully created a responsive payment link that hundreds of customers are using to make payments from Zoho.
- Created an efficient and seamless UX for users to view invoices and payments made through the gateway.
- Integrated 3 payment methods successfully Nash Pay, Mpesa and Bank (Equity)

Nash Treasury (08/2021 - 11/2022)

- Spear headed the development of the UI from the ground up.
 Created the Single Page Application using React JS and Redux toolkit.
- Evaluated the APIs needed based on the designs provided. Ensured some endpoints could be reused or repurposed for new features.
- Successfully deployed the app on my allocated environment on Azure resource group.
- Optimized the app, therefore improving performance by 45%.

Quickteller for Business (08/2020 - 02/2021)

- Successfully deployed QTB version 2 using docker and Jeakins.
- Restructured class components in the frontend codebase to functional components. This reduced the bundle size of the project by 36%.
- Improved user experience by 45% on Quickteller for business.
- Liaised with clients having issues with the new version. Assisted them with issues like adding multiple branches of their businesses and adding employees.

CERTIFICATES

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (03/2020) ♂

LANGUAGES

English Kiswahili
Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Sudoku & Puzzles

Travelling

Playing Chess

Reading fictional novels